Danny Kaye and Sylvia Fine Collection
Music Division, Library of Congress
- Business Papers, 1938-1992 (Box 439-440, 533-535, 551-591, 623-624, 635, 768-769, 774-775, 793, Mapcase folder 3-4)
  - Danny Kaye Performance Files, 1938-1989
    Materials documenting Kaye's public activities as a performer on screen and television and his humanitarian activities on behalf of children, members of the military, and performing arts organizations. Includes correspondence, programs, schedules, photographs, clippings, set lists, theater seating charts and layouts, cast information, publicity material, posters, contracts, and scripts.
    Arranged in six sub-subseries: Stage Appearances, Conducting Appearances, Films, Public Service, Television Appearances, and Theatrical Productions.
    - Stage Appearances, 1946-1980
      Correspondence, box office statements, contracts, clippings, notes, invitations, programs, set lists and timing, cast information, schedules, theater seating charts and layouts, travel arrangements, and photographs documenting Kaye's stage appearances.
      Arranged chronologically by event date.
      - Contracts, 1946-1955 (Box-folder 551/1)
      - 1934 Japan/Greater Marcus Show, 1934, Program only. (Box-folder 551/2)
      - 1946 Chicago/Chicago Theatre, 1946, October, Includes photographs of Danny Kaye. (Box-folder 551/3)
      - 1948 Germany, 1948, May-March (Box-folder 551/4)
      - 1948 London/Palladium, 1948, October-November, Correspondents include Jack Benny, Douglas Fairbanks, Jr., and Vi Marriott. (Box-folder 551/5)
      - 1949 National Film Award Supper, 1949 (Box-folder 793/6)
      - 1949 London/Palladium, 1949, June, Includes fan-created typescript of Kaye performance (Box-folder 551/6)
      - 1951 London/Palladium, 1951, May-June, Correspondents include Vivian Leigh and Laurence Olivier. (Box-folder 551/7)
      - 1952 San Francisco/Curran Theatre, 1952, September, Correspondents include Jack Benny and Billy Eckstine.; Includes drawing of Danny Kaye. (Box-folder 551/8)
      - 1953 New York City/RKO Palace Theatre, 1953, January-April, Correspondents include Irene Selznick. (Box-folder 551/9)
      - 1954 Philadelphia/Schubert Theatre, 1954, February-March (Box-folder 551/10)
      - 1954 South Africa, 1954, May-June (Box-folder 551/11)
      - 1955 London/Palladium, 1955, May-July (Box-folder 551/12)
      - 1956 Washington DC/Carter Barron Amphitheatre, 1956, August, Correspondents include George V. Allen, Frances Bolton, Felix Frankfurter, William Fulbright, Philip Graham, Hubert H. Humphrey, John Sparkman, and Stuart Symington.; Includes photographs of Danny Kaye. (Box-folder 551/13)
      - 1956 Chicago/Shubert Theatre, 1956, September, Includes photographs of Danny Kaye. (Box-folder 551/14)
      - 1956 Chicago/Shubert Theatre, Correspondence - Sumski, Dulcie, October 1956-January 1957 (Box-folder 551/15)
      - 1957 Boston/Colonial Theatre, 1957, March-April, Includes photographs. (Box-folder 551/16-17)
      - 1957 Boston/Boston Symphony Orchestra, 1957, April 3, Correspondents include Sylvia Fine, Eddie Fisher, Dena Kaye, Bruce Rabb, and Daniel Selznick. (Box-folder 551/18)
      - 1958 Los Angeles/Greek Theatre, 1958, July-August, Correspondents include Al Campanis and Joan Scully. (Box-folder 551/19)
      - 1956 Toronto, Canada/Canadian National Exposition, 1958, August-September, Correspondents include Samuel Shopsowitz. (Box-folder 551/20)
      - 1959 San Francisco/Curran Theatre, 1959, March, Correspondents include Carol Channing and Dena Kaye.; Includes children's drawings of Danny Kaye. (Box-folder 551/21-22)
      - 1959 Sydney, Australia/Empress Theatre, 1959, June 18-July 18 (Box-folder 551/23-24)
      - 1959 Melbourne, Australia/Princess Theatre, 1959, July 20-August 15 (Box-folder 551/25-26)
      - 1959 Australia Legal Materials, 1959, Jume-August (Box-folder 551/27)
      - 1959 London/Palladium, 1959, October 26, Program only. (Box-folder 551/28)
      - 1960 Las Vegas/Desert Inn, 1960, July (Box-folder 551/29, 623/3)
      - 1961 Waikiki/Waikiki Shell/50th State Fair, 1961, June 30-July 4 (Box-folder 552/1, 769/2)
      - 1961 Washington, DC/Carter Barron Amphitheatre, 1961, July 17-31, Correspondents include Abraham Ribicoff and Senators Joseph F. Clark, Jacob Javits, and Stuart Symington. (Box-folder 552/2)
      - 1961 Framingham, Mass./Carousel Theatre, 1961, July 31-August 6 (Box-folder 552/3)
      - 1961 Warwick, R.I./Warwick Musical Theatre, 1961, August 7-13 (Box-folder 552/4)
      - 1961 Wallingford, Conn./Oakdale Musical Theatre, 1961, August 14-20 (Box-folder 552/5)
      - 1961 Las Vegas/Desert Inn, 1961, October-November (Box-folder 552/6)
      - 1961 Summer Theatre Contracts, 1961 (Box-folder 552/7)
      - 1962 Tahoe, Nev./Harrah's, 1962, May (Box-folder 552/8, 769/3)
      - 1962 Los Angeles/Greek Theatre, July 23-August 4 (Box-folder 552/9)
      - 1963 Spring Contracts, 1963 (Box-folder 552/10)
      - 1963 Toronto/O'Keefe Centre, 1963, March 25-30 (Box-folder 552/11)
      - 1963 New York/Ziegfeld Theatre, 1963, April 10-May 11 (Box-folder 552/12-17, 635/5)
      - 1963 Las Vegas/Desert Inn, 1963, May, Includes photographs of Danny Kaye. (Box-folder 552/18)
      - 1964 Appearance Requests, 1964 (Box-folder 552/19)
      - 1964 Las Vegas/Desert Inn, 1964 May (Box-folder 552/20)
      - 1965, 1967 Appearance Requests, 1965, 1967 (Box-folder 552/21-22)
      - 1967 Las Vegas/Desert Inn, 1967, June 6-July 4, Includes photographs of Danny Kaye. (Box-folder 552/23)
      - 1968 Appearances, 1968, Includes photographs of Danny Kaye. (Box-folder 552/25-28)
      - 1968 General Information, 1968 (Box-folder 553/1-3)
      - 1968 Phoenix, Ariz./Phoenix Star Theatre, 1968, January 22-28 (Box-folder 553/4)
      - 1968 San Carlos, Calif./Circle Star Theatre, 1968, March (Box-folder 553/5)
      - 1968 Montreal/Place des Arts, 1968, June 3-15 (Box-folder 553/6)
      - 1968 Toronto/O'Keefe Centre, 1968, June 17-22 (Box-folder 553/7)
      - 1968 Seattle/Opera House, 1968, June 24-29 (Box-folder 553/8)
      - 1968 Portland, Ore./Civic Auditorium, 1968, July 1-6 (Box-folder 553/9)
      - 1968 Buffalo, N. Y./Melody Fair, 1968, July 15-20 (Box-folder 553/10)
      - 1968 Washington, DC/Carter Barron Amphitheatre, 1968, July 22-28 (Box-folder 553/11)
      - 1968, Framingham, Mass./Carousel Theatre, 1968, July 29-August 3 (Box-folder 553/12)
      - 1968 Warwick, R.I./Warwick Musical Theatre, 1968, August 5-11 (Box-folder 553/13)
      - 1968 Wallingford, Conn./Oakdale Musical Theatre 1968, Includes photographs of Danny Kaye. (Box-folder 553/14)
      - 1968 Lake Tahoe/Sahara-Tahoe Hotel, 1968, August 24-September 16 (Box-folder 553/15)
      - 1969 Lake Tahoe/Sahara-Tahoe Hotel, 1969, November 10-December 7, Includes photographs. (Box-folder 553/16)
      - 1969 Las Vegas/International Hotel, 1969, November 10-December7 (Box-folder 553/17)
      - 1980 London/Palladium, 1980, November 7 (Box-folder 553/18)
    - Conducting Appearances, 1954-1986
      Correspondence, clippings, notes, invitations, programs, schedules, travel arrangements, photographs, and fan mail, especially from friends and colleagues.
      - 1954 Philadelphia/Philadelphia Orchestra, 1954, March, Correspondents include Eugene Ormandy. (Box-folder 553/19)
      - 1954 Los Angeles/Hollywood Bowl, 1954, August 5, Correspondents include José Ferrar. (Box-folder 553/20)
      - 1957 Philadelphia/Philadelphia Orchestra, 1957, January 26, Correspondents include Eugene Ormandy. (Box-folder 553/21)
      - 1957 Hollywood Bowl/Los Angeles Philharmonic, 1957, August 3, Correspondents include Norman Bel Geddes, Douglas Fairbanks, Jr., Nedda and Joshua Logan, Laurence Olivier, Eleanor Roosevelt, and Bayard Swope. (Box-folder 553/22)
      - 1958 Carnegie Hall/New York Philharmonic, 1958, March 10 (Box-folder 553/23)
      - 1959 London Palladium/London Philharmonic, 1959, October 26 (Box-folder 553/24)
      - 1960 Requests, 1960 (Box-folder 553/25)
      - 1961 Detroit/Detroit Symphony Orchestra, 1961, October 13, Includes transcript of an interview with Danny Kaye. (Box-folder 553/26)
      - 1962 Oklahoma City/Oklahoma City Symphony Orchestra, 1962, January 26 (Box-folder 553/27)
      - 1962 Philharmonic Auditorium/Los Angeles Philharmonic, 1962, April 3 (Box-folder 553/28)
      - 1962 Washington, DC/DAR Constitution Hall/National Symphony Orchestra, 1962, October 19 (Box-folder 553/29)
      - 1962 Requests, 1962, Correspondents include Eugene Ormandy. (Box-folder 553/30)
      - 1963, Buffalo, N.Y./Buffalo Philharmonic, 1963, April 5 (Box-folder 553/31)
      - 1963-1964 Requests, 1963-1964, Correspondents include Richard J. Daley, Henry J. Kaiser, Irv Kupcinet, and George Smathers. (Box-folder 553/32-33)
      - 1964 Philadelphia Orchestra Correspondence, 1964-1965, Correspondents include Eugene Ormandy. (Box-folder 553/34)
      - 1965 New York Philharmonic/Lincoln Center, 1965, March 29 (Box-folder 553/35)
      - 1965 St. Louis/St. Louis Symphony Orchestra, 1965, April 12, Correspondents include August A. Busch, Jr., Morton D. May, and Stuart Symington.; Includes photographs of Danny Kaye. (Box-folder 554/1)
      - 1965 San Francisco Symphony/War Memorial Opera House, 1965, December 5, Correspondents include Jack Benny and Sylvia Fine. (Box-folder 554/2)
      - 1965 Boston Symphony Orchestra Correspondence, 1968, Correspondents include Rosario Mazzeo. (Box-folder 554/3)
      - 1965 Requests, 1965 (Box-folder 554/4)
      - 1966 London Philharmonic Orchestra/Royal Albert Hall, 1966, February 15, Correspondents include Dail Ambler, Fleur Cowles, and Harry Ellis Dickson. (Box-folder 554/5)
      - 1966 Toronto Symphony/Massey Hall, 1966, November 14 (Box-folder 554/6)
      - 1966 Requests, 1966 (Box-folder 554/7-9)
      - 1967 Gadna Israel National Youth Orchestra, 1967-1968, Folder 17 includes correspondence from Prince Bernhard of the Netherlands and photographs of Danny Kaye. (Box-folder 554/10-19)
      - 1967-1968 Requests, 1967-1968 (Box-folder 554/20-21)
      - 1969 Honolulu Concert Hall/Honolulu Symphony Orchestra, 1969, April 13, Correspondents include Harry Ellis Dickson and Shigeto Kanemoto. (Box-folder 554/22)
      - 1969 Boston Symphony Orchestra/Symphony Hall, 1969, April 20 (Box-folder 554/23)
      - 1969 Pittsburgh Symphony Correspondence, 1969 (Box-folder 554/24)
      - 1970-1974 Correspondence, 1970, January 15, Correspondents include Louis, Earl Montbatten. (Box-folder 554/25)
      - 1970 Cincinnati Symphony Orchestra/Music Hall, 1970, January 15 (Box-folder 554/26)
      - 1971 Boston Pops/Symphony Hall, 1971, May 15 (Box-folder 554/27)
      - 1972 Pittsburgh Symphony Orchestra/Heinz Hall, 1972, May 20 (Box-folder 554/28)
      - 1972 "Look-In" at the Metropolitan Opera, 1972, January 4-5, Correspondents include Helen Gurley Brown.; Includes photographs of Danny Kaye. (Box-folder 554/29-30)
      - 1973 Los Angeles Philharmonic/Dorothy Chandler Pavilion, 1973, February 3 (Box-folder 554/31)
      - 1973 Monaco/L'Orchestre Nationale de L'Opera de Monte Carlo, 1973, March 14, Correspondents include Princess Grace of Monaco.; Includes photographs of Danny Kaye. (Box-folder 555/1)
      - 1973 Minneapolis/Minnesota Orchestra, 1973, June 16 (Box-folder 555/2)
      - 1973 Kansas City, Mo./Kansas City Philharmonic, 1973, November 2, Correspondents include Stuart Symington. (Box-folder 555/3)
      - 1974 New York/"Look-In" at the Metropolitan Opera, 1974, March-April (Box-folder 555/4)
      - 1974 Houston Symphony/Jesse H. Jones Hall for the Performing Arts, 1974, May 11 (Box-folder 555/5)
      - 1974 Manchester, England/Hallé Orchestra, 1974, May 23 (Box-folder 555/6-8)
      - 1974 Chicago Symphony Orchestra, 1974, June 9, Correspondents include Helen Gurley Brown and Irv Kupcinet. (Box-folder 555/9)
      - 1974 Los Angeles Philharmonic/Dorothy Chandler Pavilion, 1974, November 10, Program only. (Box-folder 555/10)
      - 1974 Malmö, Sweden/Malmö Symphony Orchestra, 1974, December 3 (Box-folder 555/11)
      - 1975 Seattle Symphony Orchestra/Opera House, 1975, June 8 (Box-folder 555/12)
      - 1975 Sydney, Australia/Sydney Symphony Orchestra, 1975, July 26, Includes photographs of Danny Kaye. (Box-folder 555/13)
      - 1975 Melbourne, Australia/Melbourne Symphony Orchestra, 1975, August 2, Includes photographs of Danny Kaye. (Box-folder 555/14)
      - 1975 London, England/London Symphony Orchestra/Royal Festival Hall, 1975, September 27, Correspondents include Princess Margaret.; Includes photographs of Danny Kaye, Sylvia Fine, and Princess Margaret. (Box-folder 555/15-16)
      - 1976 New Haven, Conn., 1976, April 24, Correspondents include Kingman Brewster, Helen Gurley Brown, and Philip K. Nelson.; Includes photographs of Danny Kaye and Sylvia Fine. (Box-folder 555/17)
      - 1976 Jerusalem/Jerusalem Symphony Orchestra, 1976, May 4, Correspondents include Teddy Kollek and Joan Valerie. (Box-folder 555/18)
      - 1977 Montreal/Orchestra Symphonique dê Montrêal, 1977, March 2 (Box-folder 555/19)
      - 1977 New York/"Look-In" at the Metropolitan Opera, 1977, April (Box-folder 555/20)
      - 1977 Dallas Symphony Orchestra/Music Hall at Fair Park, 1977, September 24, Correspondents include Stanley Marcus. (Box-folder 555/21)
      - 1977 San Diego Symphony Orchestra/Civic Hall, 1977, October 26, Correspondents include Buzzie Bavasi and Peter Erös. (Box-folder 555/22)
      - 1977 Copenhagen, Denmark/Royal Philharmonic Orchestra, 1977, November 17, Includes photographs of Danny Kaye. (Box-folder 555/23)
      - 1978 Cleveland Orchestra/Severance Hall, 1978, May 14, Includes photograph of Danny Kaye (Box-folder 555/24)
      - 1978 San Antonio Symphony/Theatre for the Performing Arts 1978, September 30 (Box-folder 555/25)
      - 1979 Syracuse Symphony Orchestra/Civic Center, 1979, March 31 (Box-folder 555/26)
      - 1979 Amsterdam, Holland/Royal Concertgebouworkest, 1979, June 22 (Box-folder 555/27)
      - 1979 Aspen, Colo./Aspen Festival Orchestra, 1979 June 28 (Box-folder 555/28)
      - 1979 New Orleans Symphony Orchestra/Theatre of the Performing Arts, 1979, September 15 (Box-folder 556/1)
      - 1980 Jerusalem, Israel Planning Trip, 1980, July (Box-folder 556/2)
      - 1981 Portland/Oregon Symphony Orchestra, 1981, September 12 (Box-folder 556/3)
      - 1981-1985 Requests, 1981-1985 (Box-folder 556/4)
      - 1982 Vancouver Canada/Vancouver Symphony Orchestra, 1982, February 20 (Box-folder 556/5)
      - 1982 Buffalo, N. Y./Buffalo Philharmonic/Kleinhans Music Hall, 1982, March 21 (Box-folder 556/6)
      - 1983 Copenhagen, Denmark/Det Kongelige Kapel, 1983, November 21 (Box-folder 556/7)
      - 1984 Salt Lake City/Utah Symphony, 1984, May 5, Includes photographs of Danny Kaye. (Box-folder 556/8)
      - 1984 Montreal/L'Orchestre Symphonique dê Montrêal, 1984, June 8, Correspondents include Leo Kolber.; Includes photographs of Danny Kaye. (Box-folder 556/9)
      - 1985 Los Angeles/USC Trojan Marching Band/Dodger Stadium, 1985, April 15, Correspondents include Kirk and Anne Douglas, Ross Hunter, Teddy Kollek, and Jacques Mapes.; Includes photographs of Danny Kaye. (Box-folder 556/10)
      - 1985 Los Angeles Philharmonic/Hollywood Bowl, 1985, September 8 (Box-folder 556/11-13)
      - 1986 Baltimore Symphony Orchestra/Meyerhoff Symphony Hall, 1986, May 18 (Box-folder 556/14)
      - 1986 Teton Village Wyoming/Grand Teton Music Festival, 1986, August 23 (Box-folder 556/15)
      - General Information, 1961-1979, undated (Box-folder 556/16)
    - Public Service, 1945-1986
      Correspondence, children's artwork, clippings, notes, schedules, travel arrangements, and photographs. Additional materials are found in the Photographs, Scrapbooks, Clippings, and Honors series.
      Arranged alphabetically by organization name, then chronologically therein.
      - Academy of Motion Picture Arts and Sciences, 1952-1968 (Box-folder 556/17)
      - Academy of Motion Picture Arts and Sciences, Jean Hersholt Award, 1982, March, Correspondents include Michael deBakey, Anne and Kirk Douglas, June Golden, Slade Gorton, Walter Haas, Holly Hitzing, Michael Jackson, Norman Jewison, Leo Kolber, Teddy Kollek, Peter Kriendler, Bowie Kuhn, Dino de Laurentiis, Janet Leigh, Tehmi and Mehli Mehta, Delbert Mann, Eugene Ormandy, Casey Ribicoff, and David Wolper. (Box-folder 556/18)
      - AFL-CIO/Murray-Green Humanitarian Award, 1978, May 18, Correspondents include Helen Gurley Brown and Max Rabb. (Box-folder 556/19)
      - American Cancer Society, 1981 (Box-folder 556/20)
      - American Friends of Hebrew University/Scopus Award, 1977, May 18 (Box-folder 556/21)
      - American Legion Philadelphia Variety Post 713/Cohen Award, 1958 (Box-folder 556/22)
      - "A" Miscellaneous, 1958-1985 (Box-folder 556/23)
      - Ben-Gurion University of the Negev/Lifetime Achievement Award, 1982 (Box-folder 556/24)
      - Beverly Hills B'nai B'rith/Man of the Year, 1958 (Box-folder 556/25)
      - Big Brothers of America/Big Brother of the Year Award, 1957, Correspondents include Dwight D. Eisenhower.; Includes photographs of Danny Kaye. (Box-folder 556/26)
      - Borough of Brooklyn/King of Brooklyn, 1986, June 7 (Box-folder 556/27, 439/8)
      - Boy Scouts of America/Silver Buffalo Award/Danny Kaye Day, 1956, 1962 (Box-folder 556/28)
      - Brandeis University, 1956, 1958, 1982 (Box-folder 556/29)
      - "B" Miscellaneous, 1956-1965 (Box-folder 556/30)
      - Canadian Society for the Weitzmann Institute of Science, 1979 (Box-folder 556/31)
      - Canisius College/Peter Canisius Medal, 1982 (Box-folder 556/32)
      - Carnegie Foundation/Wateler Peace Prize, 1981, April 16 (Box-folder 556/33)
      - Colgate University/Honorary Doctorate of Humane Letters, 1977, May 29 (Box-folder 556/34)
      - Columbia University/Honorary Doctorate of Humane Letters, 1987, May 13 (Box-folder 556/35)
      - "C" Miscellaneous, 1961-1963, 1968 (Box-folder 556/36)
      - Denmark, Order of the Dannebrog, 1986, November (Box-folder 556/37)
      - "D" Miscellaneous, 1978 (Box-folder 556/38)
      - Eleanor Roosevelt Memorial Foundation, 1963-1965, Includes photographs of Danny Kaye. (Box-folder 556/39)
      - "E" Miscellaneous, 1958, 1969, 1975 (Box-folder 556/40)
      - Fight for Sight "Lights On," 1969 (Box-folder 557/1)
      - Food for Peace, 1961-1962, Correspondents include George McGovern. (Box-folder 557/2)
      - France, Legion of Honor, 1986 (Box-folder 557/3)
      - "F" Miscellaneous, 1963-1964, 1983-1984 (Box-folder 557/4)
      - General Rose Memorial Hospital, 1955, 1961 (Box-folder 557/5)
      - "G" Miscellaneous, 1955, 1963, 1977 (Box-folder 557/6)
      - Hadassim Children's Village, 1956 (Box-folder 557/7)
      - Hamilton College/Honorary Doctorate in Humane Letters, 1973, May 27 (Box-folder 557/8)
      - Hans Christian Andersen Club, 1962 (Box-folder 557/9)
      - Head Start Program Launch, 1965, June 30 (Box-folder 557/10)
      - "H" Miscellaneous, 1952-1956, 1970, 1973 (Box-folder 557/11)
      - Imperial WAIF Ball, 1965 (Box-folder 557/12)
      - International Center for the Disabled/Special Recognition Award for Outstanding Service, 1982, October 20 (Box-folder 557/13)
      - International League of the Rights of Man, 1969-1976 (Box-folder 557/14)
      - Israel, 1956-1973, 1958-1973; Correspondents include Daniel Barenboim, Memi de-Shalit, Teddy Kollek, Irv Kupcinet, Joseph Meyerhoff, Max Rabb, Yitzak Rabin, and Ezer Weizman.; Includes photographs of Danny Kaye. (Box-folder 557/15-22)
      - Israel Bonds, 1969-1981 (Box-folder 557/23-27)
      - "I" Miscellaneous, 1951, 1958, 1968, 1979 (Box-folder 557/28)
      - Jabotinsky Foundation/Jabotinsky Centennial Medal, 1981, November 11 (Box-folder 557/29)
      - Jewish Big Brothers Association of Los Angeles, 1956 (Box-folder 557/30)
      - Jewish Community House of Bensonhurst/Inspiration of Youth Award, 1957-1958 (Box-folder 557/31)
      - Junior Olympics, Copenhagen, 1967, Includes photographs of Danny Kaye. (Box-folder 557/32)
      - "J" Miscellaneous, 1955, 1959, 1964, 1967 (Box-folder 557/33)
      - Kennedy Center Benefit, 1971 (Box-folder 557/34)
      - Kennedy Center/Honors, 1984-1985, Correspondents include Mikhail Baryshnikov, Helen Gurley Brown, Claudette Colbert, Dom DeLuise, Kirk Douglas, Jacob Javits, Harvey Korman, Teddy Kollek, Sol Linowitz, Frank McCarthy, Jacques Pepin, Robert Schuller, George Stevens, and Martha Stewart. (Box-folder 557/35-37, 635/6)
      - Lane Bryant Annual Award, 1957-1958 (Box-folder 557/38)
      - Linus Pauling Award, 1984 (Box-folder 557/39)
      - Lions Club International/Humanitarian Award, 1974, Includes photographs of Danny Kaye. (Box-folder 557/40)
      - Los Angeles World Affairs Council, 1972-1973 (Box-folder 557/41)
      - Massachusetts Committee, Catholics, Protestants and Jews/Citation, 1962, Correspondents include Barney Balaban, John F. Collins, and Max Rabb. (Box-folder 557/42)
      - Miscellaneous, 1956, 1962, undated, Oversize items including Maryvale, Scholastic, and United Fund. (Box-folder 439/9)
      - "M" Miscellaneous, 1955, 1957, 1961, 1963, 1966, 1968 (Box-folder 557/43)
      - National Citizens' Commission on International Cooperation, 1966 (Box-folder 557/44)
      - National Conference of Christians and Jews, 1957, 1963, 1966, 1975, 1977 (Box-folder 557/45)
      - National Institute of Social Sciences/Gold Medal, 1966-1967, Correspondents include Frank Pace. (Box-folder 557/46)
      - "N" Miscellaneous, 1957-1958, 1962-1968, 1975-1976, 1982, Includes photographs. (Box-folder 557/47)
      - "O" Miscellaneous, 1958, 1960, 1964, 1968 (Box-folder 557/48)
      - Philadelphia Fellowship Commission/National Fellowship Award, 1986, May 20 (Box-folder 557/49)
      - President's Committee on the Employment of the Handicapped, Festival of the Arts, 1976 (Box-folder 557/50)
      - "P" Miscellaneous, 1957, 1974, 1978 (Box-folder 557/51)
      - Rebild National Park Society, 1972-1973, 1978 (Box-folder 558/1)
      - Requests to Appear, 1959-1962, 1966-1967, 1969, Correspondents include John Chancellor and Vincent Price. (Box-folder 558/2-6)
      - Requests to Appear on Honorary Committees, 1965, August-1967, March, Correspondents include George Jessel and Gregory Peck. (Box-folder 558/7-8)
      - Roosevelt University/Alumni Award, 1957-1958, Correspondents include Irv Kupcinet. (Box-folder 558/9)
      - "R" Miscellaneous, 1955, 1962, 1977 (Box-folder 558/10)
      - Spokane Expo/Humanitarian Award, 1974 (Box-folder 558/11)
      - "S" Miscellaneous, 1962-1963, 1966-1967, 1982, Includes photographs. (Box-folder 558/12)
      - Theatrical Square Club/Tribute, 1963, April 28, Includes photographs of Danny Kaye. (Box-folder 558/13)
      - Thomas A. Dooley Foundation/Splendid American Award, 1966-1967, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 558/14)
      - Travel/Mr. Travel Award, 1957 (Box-folder 558/15)
      - "T" Miscellaneous, 1956-1957, 1961, 1964 (Box-folder 558/16)
      - UN Association of the United States, 1963-1968, undated (Box-folder 558/17)
      - UNICEF, 1954-1960, Correspondents include Frances P. Bolton, Julius Cahn, and Maurice Pate. (Box-folder 558/18)
      - UNICEF, Assignment Children, 1954-1956, Correspondents include Harry Brand, Dore Schary, Jerry Wald, Walter Wanger, and Alexander Wiley.; Includes photographs of Danny Kaye and two volumes of clippings and images. (Box-folder 558/19-22, 439/10, 623/3, Mapcase folder 3)
      - UNICEF, 1956, Correspondents include Fred Friendly, Sol Linowitz, Bruce McMillan, and Maurice Pate. (Box-folder 558/23)
      - UNICEF, 1957, Correspondents include Bennett Cerf, Cass Canfield, Dorothy Friendly, Fred Friendly, Mitch Miller, Edward R. Murrow, Maurice Pate, Richard L. Simon, and Frank Stanton.; Includes photographs of Danny Kaye and his Peabody Award acceptance speech. (Box-folder 558/24-25, 768/2)